Hi this is Aaron Hale with Fitness For Life and I'm here to talk to you about the proper way to use a treadmill.
The first things first when approaching the treadmill we want to make sure the treadmill is not running.
We don't want to step on to a treadmill that somebody has left running and hasn't had the safety clip on or it's still on.
Once we have gotten to the treadmill we are ready to work.
Just step on to the treadmill go ahead and there should be a quick start or some sort of start button that will inform you how to get started on the treadmill.
Most treadmills come with speed control so you can dictate the speed and the pace at which you are walking, running and doing other sort of work in.
Also a lot of treadmills nowadays come with pre-programs if you do want to do a program or something like that a lot of these treadmills nowadays have a lot of preset programs and you can find those anywhere on the display.
The main thing with a treadmill is to always make sure that you are using the safety clip.
Any treadmill should come equipped with one.
Make sure that when you do, before you get on to the treadmill, it is just like getting into your car.
You want to make sure that you have your seatbelt on before you begin to drive.
The same principle applies when using the treadmill.
Make sure that you have your safety clip attached somewhere very securely, either to a piece of clothing, to your person and then begin working and doing your work on the treadmill.
Try not to push yourself too hard.
Everybody should kind of be aware of what their limits are as far as walking or running or doing any sort of interval work.
Mind your limits.
Try not to push them.
We always want to push our limits but we don't want to go past what our capabilities are so that is another safety aspect that we really need to take into consideration.
Push your limits but also know them and respect them.
This is Aaron Hale at Fitness For Life.
Thank you for joining us.